<?xml-model href="../verhagen_08/verhagen_08.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<ep n="1">
    <song music="OP"/>
    <dialogue by="voice" where="nd">Once upon a time... ...there was a princess grieving over the
        deaths of her mother and father. Before this princess appeared a prince traveling upon a
        white horse. His appearance gallant, and his smile gentle, the prince enveloped the princess
        in the scent of roses, and wiped away her tears. "Little one bearing up alone under grief,
        please lose not thy strength and nobility when thou growest up." "As a token of this day,
        please retain this." "Pray, shall we meet once more?" "This ring should guide thee to me."
        Was the ring from the prince meant as an engagement ring? That part was good, but because of
        the strength of her admiration for the prince, the princess made up her mind to become a
        prince herself! But is that really good for her?</dialogue>
    <card type="title">The Rose Bride </card><dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">It's late... Man, how
        much longer should I have to wait? I'm not going to be late the beginning of the new
        term.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Wakaba! What are you doing over there?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Waiting to see my boyfriend! </dialogue><dialogue by="unnamed"
        where="os">Boyfriend? Ha ha.. guessed you got dumped, then. Your "boyfriend" left the dorm
        earlier this morning.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Why, you... how could you?! </dialogue><card type="location">
        Ohtori Academy Junior and Senior High School</card>
    <dialogue by="teacher" where="os">Tenjou Utena-san. Do you plan to keep on wearing those strange
        clothes this semester?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Strange? </dialogue><dialogue by="teacher" where="os">Strange.
    </dialogue>All the boys are dressed like I am. <dialogue by="teacher" where="os">You are a girl!
        So why do you keep on wearing a boy's uniform?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">There's no rule here that says a girl can't wear a boy's
        uniform. No problem then! So, in that case...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="teacher" where="os">You little... You're going to keep evading me this semester,
        too, aren't you... </dialogue><dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Go, Utena!!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Sheesh, skunked again... </dialogue><dialogue by="unnamed"
        where="os">Oh, Utena, use my towel, too! </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Sure,
        sure, wait your turn.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Say, Tenjou, if you'd just join our basketball team, the local
        playoffs would be a sure thing!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Now look! I'm a girl, you know. I don't like playing basketball
        with a bunch of stinking, sweaty boys.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Why not? You're mighty boyish yourself, Tenjou.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Don't say such rude things.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Well then, why do you wear that boy's uniform?
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">That's "prince." </dialogue><dialogue
        by="unnamed" where="os">Huh?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Instead of a princess to be protected, I want to become a
        dashing prince.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">What's that mean? </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os"
        >That smell... It's the smell of roses. How long have I felt nostalgic over the scent of
        roses? What's going on over there? A lovers' quarrel? At least do that someplace where no
        one else can see you. Hey, hey... that's going a bit too far. Whew...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Utena! </dialogue>Wakaba.. you're heavy... <dialogue
        by="Wakaba" where="os">This is your punishment for leaving me behind this morning. Now say
        you're sorry! </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Okay, okay...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Oh, Saionji! </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os"
        >Saionji?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">You don't know who Saionji is? </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena"
        where="os">Oh, is he famous? I know who the guy in front of him is. That's got to be Kiryuu
        Touga, the Student Council President, right?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Yep! And the other guy is the Vice-President, Saionji Kyouichi.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What about her?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Ahh... that's Himemiya Anthy. </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena"
        where="os">Himemiya... Anthy...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">All she does is take care of the roses, though no one's asked
        her to. She's so weird. She'll be in our class from now on.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">So, is Saionji going out with that Himemiya girl?
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Not even! Tough old Saionji could never have any
        feelings for a girl like her. The only reason they're together is because they're both part
        of the Student Council</dialogue>. <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Wakaba... he's sort of
        your type, isn't he? </dialogue><dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Oh, I hate it when you get
        jealous! Don't you worry, I belong only to you. After all, you're much, much cooler than any
        boy!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">This is a sudden meeting, fellow Councilors...
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Miki" where="os">Saionji-san, we are the chosen members of the Rose
        Seal.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Juri" where="os">Don't forget that our one and only rule is to uphold the Code.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Touga" where="os">Saionji, we have a problem with the way you've
        been treating the Bride recently. </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">Oh, is that
        so?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Touga" where="os">Certainly, she is engaged to you currently. However, that
        doesn't mean you can do whatever you please to her.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Miki" where="os">"Whatever he pleases?" </dialogue><dialogue by="Juri" where="os"
        >"Whatever he pleases," you say? </dialogue><dialogue by="Touga" where="os">Quit abusing the
        Bride, Saionji. The existence of our Student Council is the behest of the Ends of the World.
        Should they know of this matter, the Ends of the World will be displeased.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">Stay out of this. Presently, the Bride and I are deeply in
        love. I don't want to hear complaints from the likes of you.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Miki" where="os">"Deeply in love?" </dialogue><dialogue by="Anthy" where="os"
        >Right now, I am Saionji's Bride. I will do everything he wishes.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">Well, that's how it is between us. If you're so concerned with
        the Code, then win back the Bride in a duel in accordance with the Code,
        Councilors.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Touga" where="os">Don't forget that the next duel will be soon upon-
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">I'm already looking forward to whoever it is
        that will challenge me. </dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">Ooh, that's so pretty... that rose pattern. Say, that's our
        school emblem, isn't it?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Sure looks like it. </dialogue><dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os"
        >Who'd you get it from? </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">A prince on a white
        horse. "This ring should guide thee to me."</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">What's that about? </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">I
        think someone said that to me when he gave me the ring, but I was real little then, so I
        don't remember too well.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">I know what you mean. When I was a little girl, my mama said to
        me, "You're the princess of the Onion Kingdom!" and I actually believed her.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">So your head's always been shaped like that, huh?
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Wakaba" where="os">I wonder what that's about...
        </dialogue><dialogue by="multiple" where="os">Now what's this?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What's going on here? </dialogue><dialogue by="unnamed"
        where="os">Someone's love letter got posted here.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Love letter? </dialogue><dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">hmmm,
        let's see... "so then I was dancing with you in my dreams, Saionji-san." "You were smiling
        so gently. You must think I'm such an idiot." Heh! I'll say!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">You guys are the idiots! This is such a tasteless thing to
        do.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="unnamed" where="os">Hey, if it's up there, anybody would read it.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Nice guys wouldn't read this- Wakaba... Wakaba!
        YOU sent that letter to Saionji? That Saionji jerk is not getting away with
        this...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">How should I know? Someone probably picked the letter out of
        the trash and posted it on their own.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Why did you throw it away in such a public place?
    </dialogue>What I do with my letters is my own business. <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">But,
        now that I think of it, if that sort of stupid, no, silly letter has amused anyone, then all
        the better. Was that all you wanted to talk about?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">No. You're the captain of the Kendo Club, right? You've got a
        duel with me today after school!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">What do you... So that's it. You're the next
        challenger.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What do you mean by that? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji"
        where="os">All right, then. I'll meet you after classes at the Duel Arena in the forest at
        the rear of the school.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Forest? The one that's off-limits? </dialogue><dialogue by="SGA"
        where="os">I wonder, I wonder... do you know what I wonder?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="SGB" where="os">I hear there's going to be another duel out back in the forest
        today! </dialogue><dialogue by="SGA" where="os">Oh, brave warrior, you're going to fight for
        your friend, meddlesome brave warrior!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="SGB" where="os">But beware, brave warrior... </dialogue><dialogue by="SGA"
        where="os">They fight by a Code, there in the forest.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="SGB" where="os">Do you know that, I wonder? </dialogue><dialogue by="SGA"
        where="os">I wonder, I wonder...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="multiple" where="os">Do you know what I wonder? </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena"
        where="os">What the... Now how am I supposed to get into this place, anyway? And of course,
        it's locked. Hey! That's cold! What kind of gate is this? Well, whatever. I'm going
        in!</dialogue>
    <song music="ZUM"/>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">A castle in midair? How? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji"
        where="os">So, this is your first time to see the castle, eh?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What is it? I sure couldn't see it from outside the forest.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">It's a mirage, of sorts. You can think of it as
        magic, if you like.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">A mirage? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">What
        surprises me is someone outside the Student Council possessing a Rose Seal.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Rose Seal? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">I mean
        this.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">That ring... </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">Anthy!
        Prepare us for battle!</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Himemiya... Anthy... Himemiya, what are YOU doing
        here?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">Naturally, the Bride ought to be in attendance.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Bride? That smell... It's the same, the same as
        my prince's roses.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Anthy" where="os">The person whose rose gets scattered loses the duel.
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Huh? </dialogue><dialogue by="Anthy" where="os"
        >Good luck to you.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What was that for? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os"
        >Don't toy with me, Anthy! You're the Rose Bride, in other words, MY flower. How dare you
        wish anyone else good luck?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Anthy" where="os">I'm sorry, Saionji. </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os"
        >Stupid! He does all this, and you still submit to him? </dialogue><dialogue by="Anthy"
        where="os">Saionji is the current duel champion, so he can do with me as he
        likes.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What does that mean? Isn't he supposed to be your
        boyfriend?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">So, let us begin. </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os"
        >I'm not sure what's going on here, but it doesn't matter, as long as I beat him, right?
    </dialogue>O roses of the noble castle, <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">What? More magic?
        </dialogue><dialogue by="Anthy" where="os">O Power of Dios that slumbers within me, Harken
        unto thy master and reveal to us...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">...the power to revolutionize the world! You're pretty good...
        for a girl. So you want to be the prince who saves the helpless princess?
        Unfortunately...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Oh, no! That magical sword... is real?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">I'm surprised at you. Really now, challenging the Sword of
        Dios with a simple bamboo practice sword?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Sword of Dios? </dialogue><dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">You
        don't know about the Sword of Dios? Who ARE you? You ARE an intriguing creature.</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Hey, this fight ain't over yet! </dialogue><dialogue
        by="Saionji" where="os">If you so desire, I'll gladly stain that rose with your blood, with
        but a single strike. Go ahead then, risk your life and face me... if you have the courage!
        You, a prince on a white horse, out to save a princess?</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="voice" where="nd">"Little one bearing up alone under grief, please lose not thy
        strength and nobility when thou growest up."</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Saionji" where="os">What? Stupid bitch! It can't be... I've... lost?
        Anthy...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Anthy" where="os">Take it easy, Saionji... </dialogue><dialogue by="Touga"
        where="os">This is an unexpected turn of events. And she's in junior high school? All right,
        baby. You've set my heart on fire. </dialogue><dialogue by="Utena" where="os">Ahh.. That was
        really weird, whatever happened back there. What was all that, anyway? Oh well, better just
        forget about it! Huh? You...</dialogue>
    <dialogue by="Anthy" where="os">I've been waiting for you, Utena. I am the Rose Bride, and from
        today on, I am your flower.</dialogue>
    <song music="ED"/>
</ep>
