<?xml-model href="verhagen_07/verhagen_07.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<letter>
    <!--Fixed paragraph noteation, added page numbers, placement, and added additions that I originally missed-->
    <p n="1">
        <page n="24">I received particular joy at seeing<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> within the smell of the land<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> an Old Yorkshire man of foreseer who had left
            his son a merchant in New York<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
                >,</type> to breath his last in his native land; far from the continued storms we
            met feeble situation he was in from sea sickness I had been apprehensive we should have
            lost him on the passage. Coasting the Southwest shore of Ireland on that 18th in the
            evening we made Cork<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> where we
            were (sp. where) becalmed – we met there a ship we had seen two days before at a
                distance<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> she was an armed
            vessel of Liverpool<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that had
            been at Barbados<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and was now
                returning<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> she had on
            board the Governor<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and suite
            of a Dutch settlement in the West Indies<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> lately taken by the British troops – There is not much
            appearance of verdure yet on shore – or it might in some respect afford a beautiful
            prospect – but they have a disagreeable way of decorating their coasts with gibbets (sp.
            jibbets) here and there – Is it not surprising<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> that a people so enlightened<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> so humane and so polite should have it so
                arranged<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that the first
            object striking the view of the strangers<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> who approach their shore should be an emblem of the
            severity of their laws and depravity of some of their people. Telegraphs were also to be
            seen on every eminence – this is a late invention to communicate intelligence of the
            approach of an enemy or to give orders to the ships of the Navy – they are on a line of
            communica-tion within distinct view of each other – certain figures are put up which are
            repeated from one</page>
        <page n="25"> to the other without being understood by any but those from whom the orders
            issue and the commanders of Posts. We there learnt<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> by the boats which came from the shore<type
                style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that all was as yet
                tranquil<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that they had
            only heard of the threats of Bonaparte which it was not likely<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> he would be able to put in execu-tion. After
            night a fair wind springing up<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
                >,</type> we made sail<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
            and next morning<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> we were
            abreast of Wicklow Moun-tains<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
            the land is high and elevated<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
            but we were at too great a distance to distinctly view it – On the 21st we sailed along
            the Welsh Coast and passed Holyhead – here is elevated land and lofty mountains<type
                style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> whose tops are covered with
                snow<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> which although they
            do not prepossess you with an idea of the fertility of the country<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> yet the natural Majestic grandeur of the
            asylum of the descendants of ancient Britons strikes the mind with veneration at the
            magnanimity and unfortunate valor of their ancestors who preferred breathing the air of
            freedom on Rocky Mountains<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> to
            remaining in subjection on their native fertile plains<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> and calls a sigh for their hero the gallant Caractacus.
            In the evening a Pilot comes on board and next day we arrive safe in dock here<type
                style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the pleasure we felt on the
            occasion can not well be imagined by any but those<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> who have made a long sea voyage. Altho’ this was Sunday
            and business lulled at rest<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
            yet sufficient was to be seen to give a stranger some conception of the magnitude of the
            trade carried on at this place – the many store houses<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> the multitude of ships<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> the inland canals and docks all denote wealth and
                exertion<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> these last are
            of two kind wet and dry<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the
            latter are to receive vessels to be repaired; the former are for </page>
        <page n="26">ships to unload and load in; they are made by digging spaces to such a level as
            to be of sufficient depth for the vessels that are to enter the gates of these docks at
            which the vessels<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and flow of
            the tide are received<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> are
            shut in the ebb tide by which means the water is retained that keeps the ships afloat –
            were it not for these constructions the lading and unlading would be performed with
            great inconvenience at this port which is not naturally well calculated<type
                style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the River being amazing
            shallow at low water<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and its
            entry rendered difficult from a number of sand banks. But the approximate situation of
            this place to several manufacturing town renders it the great emporium of commerce to
            the West – It is here that are deposited the stuffs of Manchester<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the cutlery of Birmingham and the woolen
            cloths of Yorkshire<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> as are
            also the produce of the west for which they are bartered – it is considered next to
            London for importance in trade: that of Africa however is a branch that is carried on
            here to some extent and is not honorable to the human spe-cies; for it is a barter of
            their fellow creatures – you must not by this imagine<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> that the slaves are brought here<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> no<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
                reason="addition">,</type> for none would be slaves after they had breathed the
            British air – they are bought in Africa for coarse clothes<type style="cursive"
                bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> arms spirits and taken to the West Indies and
            sold for the produce of these Islands<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
                >,</type> which is brought to this place and from it taken to different parts of the
            country. </page>
    </p>

    <p n="2">Coasting the Southwest shore of Ireland on that 18th in the evening we made Cork<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> where we were (sp. where) becalmed
        – we met there a ship we had seen two days before at a distance<type style="cursive"
            bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> she was an armed vessel of Liverpool<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that had been at Barbados<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and was now returning<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> she had on board the Governor<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and suite of a Dutch settlement in
        the West Indies<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> lately taken by
        the British troops – There is not much appearance of verdure yet on <type style="cursive"
            bold="yes" reason="correction">s</type>hore – or it might in some respect afford a
        beautiful prospect –<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="correction"> but they have a
            disagreeable way of decorating their coasts</type>
        <type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="correction">with gibbets</type>
        <notDoc>(sp. jibbets)</notDoc>
        <type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="correction">here and there</type> – Is it not
            surprising<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that a people so
            enlightened<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> so humane and so
        polite should have it so arranged<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
        that the first object striking the view of the strangers<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> who approach their <type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="correction" placement="above">shore</type> should be an emblem of the severity
        of their laws and depravity of some of their people. Telegraphs were also to be seen on
        every eminence – this is a late invention to communicate intelligence of the approach of an
        enemy or to give orders to the ships of the Navy – they are on a line of communica-tion
        within distinct view of each other – certain figures are put up which are repeated from one
        (p.35) to the other without being understood by any but those from <type style="cursive"
            bold="yes" reason="addition" placement="margin">whom</type> the orders issue and the
        commanders of Posts. We there learnt<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
            >,</type> by the boats which came from the shore<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> that all was as yet tranquil<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> that they had only heard of the threats of Bonaparte which it
        was not likely<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> he would be able
        to put in execu-tion. </p>

    <p n="3">After night a fair wind springing up<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
            >,</type> we made sail<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and
        next morning<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type>
        <type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition" placement="above">we</type> were abreast
        of Wicklow Moun-tains<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the land is
        high and elevated<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> but we were at
        too great a distance to distinctly view it – On the 21st we sailed along the Welsh Coast and
        passed Holyhead – here is elevated land and lofty mountains<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> whose tops are covered with snow<type style="cursive"
            bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> which although they do not prepossess you with an
        idea of the fertility of the country<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition"
            >,</type> yet the <type style="cursive" bold="no" reason="addition">natural</type>
        Majestic grandeur of the asylum of the descendants of ancient <type style="cursive"
            bold="no" reason="correction" placement="above">Britons</type> strikes the mind with
        veneration at the magnanimity and unfortunate valor of their ancestors who preferred
        breathing the air of freedom on Rocky Mountains<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> to remaining in subjection on their native fertile
            plains<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and calls a sigh for
        their hero the gallant Caractacus. </p>
    <p n="4">In the evening a Pilot comes on board and next day we arrive safe in dock here<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the pleasure we felt on the
        occasion can not well be imagined by any but those<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> who have made a long sea voyage. Altho’ this was Sunday and
        business lulled at rest<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> yet
        sufficient was to be seen to give a stranger some conception of the magnitude of the trade
        carried on at this place – the many store houses<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> the multitude of ships<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> the inland canals and docks all denote wealth and
            exertion<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> these last are of
        two kind wet and dry<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the latter
        are to receive vessels to be repaired; the former are for (p.36) ships to unload and load
        in; they are made by digging spaces to such a level <type style="blackOut" bold="no" reason="blackOut"/> as to be of
        sufficient depth for the vessels that are to enter the gates of these docks at which the
            vessels<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and flow of the tide
        are received<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> are shut in the ebb
        tide by which <type style="cursive" bold="no" reason="addition" placement="above"
            >means</type> the water is retained that keeps the ships afloat – were it not for these
        constructions the lading and unlading would be performed with great inconvenience at this
        port which is not naturally well calculated<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> the River being amazing shallow at low water<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> and its entry rendered difficult
        from a number of sand banks. </p>

    <p n="5">But the approximate situation of this place to <type style="blackOut" bold="no" reason="blackOut"/>
        <type style="cursive" bold="no" reason="addition" placement="above">several</type>
        <type style="blackOut" bold="no" reason="blackOut"/> manufacturing town <type style="blackOut" bold="no" reason="blackOut"/>. renders it the great
        emporium of commerce to the West – It is here that are deposited the stuffs of
            Manchester<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> the cutlery of
        Birmingham and the woolen cloths of Yorkshire<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> as are also the produce of the west for which they are
        bartered – it is considered next to London for importance in trade: that of Africa however
        is a branch <type style="blackOut" bold="yes" reason="blackOut"/> that is carried on here to some extent <type style="blackOut" bold="no" reason="blackOut"/> and is not <type style="blackOut" bold="yes" reason="blackOut"/> honorable to the human spe-cies; for it is
        a barter of their fellow creatures – you must not by this imagine<type style="cursive"
            bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> that the slaves are brought here<type
            style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> no<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> for none would be slaves after they had breathed the British
        air – they are bought in Africa for coarse clothes<type style="cursive" bold="yes"
            reason="addition">,</type> arms spirits and taken to the West Indies and sold for the
        produce of these Islands<type style="cursive" bold="yes" reason="addition">,</type> which is
        brought to this place and from it taken to different parts of the country.</p>
</letter>