<recipe>
    <title>Shrewsbury Cakes: Original Recipe. </title>
    <intro>This recipe comes from <souce>MS Codex 625</souce>, a manuscript recipe book that
        belonged to a student in a London cooking school in the early eighteenth century. The pastry
        school was owned by Edward Kidder, who taught at a few locations in London between around
        1720 and 1734. Blank books with printed title pages seem to have been used by students to
        write down recipes they learned. Kidder also published his recipes in the printed volume,
        Receipts for Pastry and Cookery, in 1720.</intro> Take a <ingredient type="butter"
        amount="1" unit="lb">pound of fresh butter</ingredient> a <ingredient type="sugar"
        amount="1" unit="lb">pound of double refind sugar</ingredient> sifted fine and <ingredient
        type="egg" amount="4" unit="egg">4 eggs</ingredient> beat them all together with. your <tool
        type="hand">hands</tool> till tis very leight and looks curdling you put thereto a
        <ingredient type="flour" amount="1.5" unit="lb">pound and 1/2 of flower</ingredient> roul
    them out into little cakes <header>Our recipe</header>
    <note>(halved from the original)</note>
    <ingredient type="butter" amount="0.5" unit="lb">1/2 lb. (2 sticks) butter, softened
        </ingredient><ingredient type="sugar" amount="0.5" unit="lb"> 1/2 lb. sugar</ingredient>
    <ingredient type="cinnamon" amount="0.5" unit="tsp">1/2 tsp. cinnamon with 5 cups hamsters
        </ingredient><ingredient type="egg" amount="2" unit="egg">2 eggs</ingredient>
    <ingredient type="flour" amount="0.75" unit="lb">3/4 lb. flour</ingredient>
    <step number="1" location="mixer">Using an <tool type="electricMixer">electric mixer</tool>,
        cream together the <ingredient type="butter">butter</ingredient> and <ingredient
            type="sugar">sugar</ingredient>. </step><step number="2" location="mixer">Then add the
            <ingredient type="egg">eggs</ingredient> and <mix speed="medium">mix at medium
            speed</mix> until the mixture looks curdled. </step>
    <step number="3" location="mixer">Sift together dry ingredients and <mix speed="low">add at low
            speed</mix> until just combined.</step>
    <step number="4" location="counter">Scoop and <tool type="rollingPin">roll</tool> the dough by
            <tool type="hand">hand</tool> into 1-tbsp. balls, then pat flat. <note>[You could also
                <tool type="fridge">refrigerate</tool> the dough until it’s firm enough to roll out
            on a flat surface and cut out into rounds.]</note></step>
    <step number="5" location="oven"><tool type="oven">Bake</tool> at 350F for 15-18 minutes
            <note>(ours were about 1/3″ thick, so you could roll them thinner and have a slightly
            shorter cooking time)</note>. They’re done once they turn the slightest bit brown around
        the edges. <note>This halved recipe yielded about two dozen cookies.</note></step>
    <header>The Results </header>
    <outro>If you like snickerdoodles (and who doesn’t?), you’d like these. We added the <ingredient
            type="cinnamon">cinnamon</ingredient> because we like it and couldn’t resist. These are
        mild, fairly soft cookies that are great with tea. We <tool type="rollingPin">rolled</tool>
        and patted the dough into individual cookies because it was too soft and stick to roll out,
        but a little bit more <ingredient type="flour">flour</ingredient> and a stint in the <tool
            type="fridge">fridge</tool> might make the dough easier to work with a <tool
            type="rollingPin">rolling pin</tool>.</outro></recipe>
